

Benjamin Obetta

Mobile Application Engineer

Phone: 07039612093 Email: obettabenjamin44@gmail. Git: https://github.com/obetta1,

I am a skilled and adaptive Mobile developer with a knowledge of utilising technological tools in areas such as Java and Kotlin, Flutter, Dart. I have 4+ years of experience in building android applications with kotlin and cross platform applications with Flutter. I possess a comprehensive understanding of mobile application development principles and best practices. I am adept at utilizing RESTful APIs, GraphQL APIs and working with JSON data for efficient integration of backend services. Throughout my career, I have demonstrated knowledge of various mobile app design patterns and architectures, such as MVC and MVVM. My coding style emphasizes cleanliness and maintainability to facilitate future enhancements and updates.

EXPERIENCE

Mobile *Application Engineer*Papyrus Digital Solution Limited.

Jan 2023 - Present

- Develop, and maintain high-quality cross platform applications with Flutter, that facilitate fieldwork management and sales representative monitoring.
- Create visually appealing and user-friendly interfaces that enhance the app's usability for both onsite and offsite users.
- Implement data synchronization mechanisms to enable real-time access to critical information for sales representatives in the field.
- Utilize GPS and Google location services to track and monitor the real-time location of sales representatives in the field. Implement geofencing and location-aware features to enhance fieldwork efficiency and reporting.
- Design and implement offline capabilities to ensure that the app functions smoothly even in areas with limited or no internet connectivity. Implement data caching and synchronization mechanisms for seamless offline usage.
- Collaborate effectively with team members and stakeholders, providing regular updates on project progress and addressing any technical concerns. Participate in code reviews and provide constructive feedback to peers.

Mobile *Application Engineer*Decagon Digital Learning Limited.

June 2021 - Jan 2023

- Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform.
- Implemented advance feature with top quality clean code adhering to best practices.
- Proactively identified performance bottlenecks and implemented optimizations to enhance application speed and responsiveness.
- Enhancing applications performance by identifying opportunities for improvement and making recommendations.
- Maintaining and improving existing codebases and rectifying bugs.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features
- Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability.

SKILLS

- Flutter
- Dart
- Java
- Kotlin
- State Management (BloC, Riverpod, Getx)
 - Jetpack
 - Android SDK.
 - Android Studio.
 - REST-Api.
 - GraphQl Api.

EDUCATION

Enugu State University of Science and Technology, Enugu State. August 2012 - June 2018 Bachelor of Engineering, Second Class Honour

Electrical/Electronic Engineering.

LANGUAGES

English, Igbo, Yoruba **Android Developer.** Contract. January 2022 - May 2022 **Indomidas Advertising Private Limited.**

- Built Pendora application that helps writers to unleash their creativity through poem, Quote and creative writings.
- Developed features that help users change screen background, text fonts and colour to suit their creativity and enhance user experience.
- Monitors application performance by integrating third party analytics thereby reducing user loss by crash rate.
- •Worked closely with Backend engineer, UI designer, Project Manager, and Project owner to ensure the success of the project.

Android Developer. June 2020-April 2021. Herconomy Ltd, Lagos

- Built a finance application that facilitates users' daily contributions and transfer of funds between wallets.
- Developed features that enhance easy savings according to a users' set plan.
- Monitors application performance by integrating third party analytics.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Worked closely with Backend engineer, UI designer, Project Manager, and Project owner to ensure the success of the project.
- Onboarded another Android Engineer to the project and provided support and mentoring.

PROJECTS

FieldMaxPro App: This app facilitates fieldwork management and sales representative monitoring and providing field force automation solutions.

Role: Android Engineer. Language: Flutter.

Tools: Flutter SDK, Flutter Hive, Riverpod, Firebase, Android studio.

Link: FieldMaxPro app

Eveword App: This is an e-commerce application that I built for a hair vendor that allows users to order products and services online.

Role: Flutter Engineer. Language: Futter.

Tools: Flutter SDK, Flutter Hive, BloC, Getx, Firebase, Android studio,.

Link: Eveword app

Herconomy App: This is a finance application that allows users to save easily and earn interest on their savings, with attractive features that suit users' needs.

Role: Android Engineer. Language: Kotlin.

Tools: Android studio, Android SDK, Room Database, REST APIs, GraphQL.

Link: herconomy app

Hotel Voyage App: This is a mobile application that is used for booking hotel reservations and other amenities from the comfort of your home.

Role: Android Engineer. Language: Kotlin. Link: <u>hotel voyage app</u>